Edward Corsi Papers
Edward Corsi Papers
- Activities
  - Immigration and Naturalization
    - Correspondence
      - re: Corsi-Dulles dispute, April 1955 (Box 47)
      - Notes, January 3, 1957-May 15, 1958; undated (Box 47)
    - Research data, printed material, re: Corsi-Dulles dispute, May 1953-June 1955 (Box 47)
    - Reports, printed material
      - January 1924-May 1954 (Box 47)
      - April 1955-March 1965, undated, 3 folders (Box 48)
  - LaGuardia Memorial House, Inc.
    - Correspondence
      - October 29, 1931; 1941-1947 (Box 48)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 48)
      - 1951-1956, 3 folders (Box 49)
      - Potofsky Dinner, July 21, 1961-December 12, 1963; undated; notes (Box 49)
      - Statue, "Mother Italy", March 30, 1962-May 24, 1965; includes 1 photograph (Box 49)
    - Minutes and reports, December 18, 1919; September 1945-1965; typescript and typescript carbon (Box 49)
    - Publicity and reports, 1918-1967; undated; printed material; 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965; undated; reproduction; 1 negative (Box 50)
  - Legal Records, February 15, 1949; undated; typescript (Box 50)
  - National Committee on Immigration Policy
    - Correspondence, July 31, 1945-November 12, 1946 (Box 50)
    - Reports, February 1946-June 1950; printed material (Box 50)
    - Miscellaneous reports by others
      - Economic Aspects of Immigration, September 30, 1946; first draft printed material (Box 50)
      - International Migration and One World, August 14, 1946; printed material (Box 50)
  - National Council on Naturalization and Citizenship
    - Correspondence, January 25, 1946-December 22, 1959 (Box 50)
    - Minutes and reports, 1941-1960; undated; printed material; 2 folders (Box 50)
  - National Social Welfare Assembly, Inc., March 1947-February 1948; minutes and agenda, printed material (Box 50)
  - New York State Constitutional Convention
    - Correspondence, March 16-September 29, 1938 (Box 51)
    - Reports and memoranda, March-July 1938; printed material (Box 51)
  - Order Sons of Italy in America
    - Correspondence
      - 1940-1941, 3 folders (Box 51)
      - 1942 January-May (Box 51)
      - 1942 June-September (Box 52)
    - Reports, March 1940-November 1942; typescript and typescript carbon (Box 52)
    - Agenda and brochures, July 1940-July 1950; printed material (Box 52)
  - Reports - miscellaneous, 1941-1961; undated; typescript and typescript carbon (Box 52)
  - Republicans
    - Correspondence
      - 1930-1952, 3 folders (Box 52)
      - 1953-1965 (Box 53)
    - Releases and reports, August 1947-1950; undated; printed material (Box 53)
  - United Service Organizations, October 31, 1941-September 9, 1942; correspondence (Box 53)
  - Washington applications, January 14-June 8, 1953; correspondence (Box 53)
- Published material
  - Eisenhower Administration accomplishments, Executive Branch Liaison Office, December 1953-January 1955 (Box 53)
  - Census of 1930, Apr-Jun 1930; scrapbook of newspaper clippings (Box 57)
  - Farming and Gardening
    - May 1933-June 1944 (Box 53)
    - July 1944-August 1952 (Box 54)
  - Foreign Aid, October 1947-1961 (Box 54)
  - Gambling inquiry - Frank Erickson, May-June 1950 (Box 54)
  - Italy, 1931; 1946-1953,; September 1965,; undated (Box 55)
  - Labor and Employment, May 1947-1966; includes Upton Sinclair, Letters to Judd (June 1949) (Box 55)
  - New York City Department of Welfare, Bureau of Child Welfare, Division of Day Care, [1943?]; February 1952-April 1959 (Box 55)
  - La Settimana, "rivista italiana fondata da Edward Corsi,"
    - vol. 2, nos. 7, 13, 20-23, 26-32, 24-44; vol. 3, nos. 1-17, February 14, 1936-May 3, 1937 (Oversize 2)
    - vol. 3, nos. 18-27, May 23-July 25, 1937 (Box 56)
    - vol. 3, nos. 28-32, 34-37, 39-41, August 1-November 14, 1937 (Oversize 2)
  - Preparation of the Site for the World's Fair, [April 1960] (Oversize 1)